<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on maxking&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://asychronous.in/tags/python/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on maxking&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://asychronous.in/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you mocking me?</title>
      <link>http://asychronous.in/2013/07/19/are-you-mocking-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://asychronous.in/2013/07/19/are-you-mocking-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unit testing is one of the most important parts of any project. TDD (test
driven development) is a good habit to cultivate, in case you are not convinced,
you don&#39;t know about TDD or you have never given it a try. I started using
partial TDD recently, yes only partial for what I follow is that first I write a
rough outline of the code, then I write tests and then I keep on re-factoring my
code till all the tests are passing. Though there is a little flaw in this
method according to me -- although writing tests are mostly trivial with those
easy assert statements, sometimes you may write wrong tests which make you write
wrong code too. So put more thought in writing tests than in writing
code. Although many times you will agree with me that TDD is annoying, it does
not let you do what you actually want to do (I mean the &#34;way&#34; you want to do it,
the result may be same).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So in this post I am going to talk about mocks. What are mocks? There are some
magical functions which do some abracadabra on your existing function and make
them return anything that you want without actually even thinking what they are
returning. Did I personify it a little too much? Let me explain in a little
detail with the example of where I used mocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Unit tests should be independent of environment and any other module, so that
each module can be developed separately without affecting the development of
other modules. But many a times one module depends on others and in that case
it gets messy to test those functions. In my case it was the &#34;signature&#34; rule
which uses &#34;gpg&#34; utility to verify signature of messages. Here is a snippet of
the code:&lt;/p&gt;


from mailman.utilities.gpg import GPG
 
@implementer(IRule)
class Signature:
    &#34;&#34;&#34;Look for pgp-signature.&#34;&#34;&#34;

    name=&#39;signature&#39;
    description=_(&#39;The message has pgp-signature as application/pgp-signature part&#39;)
    record = True
    def __init__(self):
        self._gpg = None

    def check(self, mlist, msg, msgdata):
        &#34;&#34;&#34;See `IRule&#34;&#34;&#34;
        gpg_dir = os.path.join(config.VAR_DIR, &#39;gpg&#39;)
        self._gpg = GPG(gpg_dir)



&lt;p&gt;So if you see in line 1 we import the GPG class from &lt;i&gt;gpg&lt;/i&gt; utility. But
when we write tests we don&#39;t want this function to &#34;actually&#34; create an instance
of GPG class and &#34;actually&#34; verify the signature because it is not a function of
signature rule and any errors or breakpoints in gpg utility may cause our tests
for the &#34;working&#34; signature rule to fail. So what do we do? We mock and then we
rock ;-). We mock the GPG instance created in signature rule to return &#34;any
specific value&#34; irrespective of the input. See the code below:&lt;/p&gt;



import mock

class TestSignatureMime(unittest.TestCase):
    &#34;&#34;&#34;Test the signature handler.&#34;&#34;&#34;

  class Dummy_GPG_True:    
      def __init__(self, dir):
          self._dir = dir
        
      def verify_inline_signature(self, data):
          return True

      def verify_detached_signature(self, data):
          return True


  @mock.patch(&#39;mailman.rules.signature.GPG&#39;, new=Dummy_GPG_True)
  def test_good_signature(self):
      result = self._rule.check(self._mlist, self._msg, {})
      self.assertTrue(result)



&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNUPG and python</title>
      <link>http://asychronous.in/2013/07/16/stuck-at-gnupg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://asychronous.in/2013/07/16/stuck-at-gnupg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this post talks about what gpg is, what are the various problems that can
be solved using gpg and about python-gnupg library which can be used to sign a
message or file using python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; For now python-gnupg allows detached signatures from file type objects, but
what if we want to verify some text with a detached signature in the form on
string in out application? StringIO module has been of some help but I am up
researching how to use it better. Once I am done with it I will resume to this
post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>