<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mailman on maxking's blog</title><link>https://asynchronous.in/tags/mailman/</link><description>Recent content in mailman on maxking's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asynchronous.in/tags/mailman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are you mocking me?</title><link>https://asynchronous.in/2013/07/19/are-you-mocking-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asynchronous.in/2013/07/19/are-you-mocking-me/</guid><description>Unit testing is one of the most important parts of any project. TDD (test driven development) is a good habit to cultivate, in case you are not convinced, you don't know about TDD or you have never given it a try. I started using partial TDD recently, yes only partial for what I follow is that first I write a rough outline of the code, then I write tests and then I keep on re-factoring my code till all the tests are passing.</description></item><item><title>Rules and Chains</title><link>https://asynchronous.in/2013/06/30/rules-and-chains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asynchronous.in/2013/06/30/rules-and-chains/</guid><description>This post talks about the basic messaging flow in mailman and then a little detail about what are rules and chains in Mailman. So a message can be injected in mailman system using a LMTP server via LMTP. LMTP(Local Mail Transfer Protocol) is a derivative of ESMTP(Extended SMTP), which is a extension of well known SMTP(Simple Mail Transfer Protocol). LMTP runner parses the message into a tuple of type (mailing_list, message, message_data) and stores it in a serialized form called python pickle(.</description></item><item><title>Gsoc 2013 - Pilot!</title><link>https://asynchronous.in/2013/06/12/gosc-into/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asynchronous.in/2013/06/12/gosc-into/</guid><description>In this post I will first start with my introduction in brief and then move on to my gsoc project. I am a undergrad student at Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur doing my majors in Department of Metallurgical and Materials Engineering expecting to pass out in 2015. This summer I will be working for GNU Mailman under Python Software Foundation for my gsoc project - Implementation of OpenPGP with Mailman.</description></item></channel></rss>